SAMUEL KAUFFMAN

PROFILE

I'm dedicated to becoming a great front end developer—or getting as close to that goal as I can. After spending the last decade working in non-profits, it was time to pursue my lifelong passion of tech. I've spent the last few months pursuing this goal, first in my spare time, then through The Iron Yard's full-time Front End Engineering bootcamp in Orlando, Florida. Now I'm ready to take the next step and work full-time as a developer. I'm hoping you'll give me that opportunity.

SKILLS

Web Development HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Angular, jQuery, Lodash, SASS, Bootstrap, JSON APIs, Git, Gitflow, Github, Bower, Gulp, Yeoman, Browser-Sync, Mocha, Chai, Responsive Design

EXPERIENCE

January 2015 - March 2015 Front End Engineering - an intensive three-month bootcamp that
The Iron Yard "forges" students into professional junior-level programmers. The
program goes far beyond tactical skills and teaches students to
think like a software engineer.

- O <u>Skedaddle</u> is a front end web application that enables a user to pick from a list of themed locations and a maximum budget for a getaway. Up to 5 round-trip flights for a weekend length trip will be supplied with a link for the user to purchase their choice.
 - Scaffolded with Gulp Angular
 - O Uses QPX Express API by Google to supply airline data
 - Coded with HTML, Javascript, Angular, and jQuery
 - Responsively Designed with Bootstrap, Sass, and CSS
 - O Version control with Git, Gitflow, and Github
- Surf No Paddle a group assignment, our team of two was challenged to mashup multiple APIs to make something new.
 After deciding to give a surf report and location using a maritime database and google maps api, Surf No Paddle was the result.
 - Uses Google Maps API and World Weather API
 - coded with HTML, Javascript and jQuery
 - Designed with Bootstrap and CSS
 - Version control with Git and Github

June 2014 - December 2014 Specialist at the Apple Store - As the first person customers meet

Apple when they enter the store, as well as the person who guided them

— advised, sold, and even set up their new products. Other roles included visual merchandising and assisting back of house team.

EXPERIENCE

October 2004 - July 2014 Central Florida Hillel Associate Director - Managed all aspects of program department; developed and administered program operational policies, procedures and systems. Through strategic vision & leadership supervised program personnel, establish annual program goals; initiated, planned, actualized and evaluated programs; maintained a relevant program. Served as the liaison to campus organizations and relevant department and programs developed strong relationships with university officials and built coalitions where appropriate.

Interim Executive Director- Assumed duties of the executive director by representing organization in community, on campuses, and at national events, oversight of board governance, prepared and managed budget and fiscal policies, solicited and collected donations and awarded grants. Managed all aspects of programming. Implemented annual combined board retreat. Administered human resources policies. Instituted a semi-annual staff day of service.

Assistant Executive Director - Board development responsibilities included preparation for meetings, recruitment, and cultivation. Managed fundraising event that led to highest net profit in organizational history. Administered human resources policies, procedures, benefits, and bi-weekly payroll. Prepared and managed budget. Awarded grants, Oversaw programming operations. Managed facility and coordination of staff and vendors. Coordinated development efforts, staffed immersive experiences, and identified strategies to decrease expenses and to refocus organization on mission during economic crisis.

Program Director - Developed and successfully implemented strategic student programming and outreach plans that increased market penetration by 300% and student leadership by 200%. Completed three straight years of successful programming under budget through an implemented action plan, successfully awarded grants, produced unique curriculum and aspects of the first alternative spring break cruises to the - Bahamas including community service, history and learning, and collaboration with other foundations, successfully recruited, coordinated, and staffed hundreds of students attending immersive experiences.

EDUCATION

2015 Front End Engineering

The Iron Yard

2001-2002

Master of Science, Sport Administration

(Physical Education) — The Florida State University

2002

Global Sport Management Program Paris, France & London, England

1997-2001

Bachelor of Science, Sport Management (Education) — The Florida State University

INTERESTS

Life Hacking, Hacking, Organizational Culture, Branding, UX, Innovation, Customer Service, Advertising, Sports, Outdoor Adventure, Traveling, and Cooking.